<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremy Worsfold</title>
    <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Jeremy Worsfold</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/media/face.jpg</url>
      <title>Jeremy Worsfold</title>
      <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling hair follicle development and formation of periodic patterns of cells.</title>
      <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/pss/shahzeb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/pss/shahzeb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The development of hair follicles starts in the early embryonic days. In this talk, I will take you through an exciting journey of what contributes to the formation of hair follicles and how pigment (colour) producing cell behave in response to these follicles to form cool periodic patterns. Don’t need an A* in GCSE biology or any complicated maths as you will see how complex biological behaviours can be modelled using some simple mathematical tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Invitation to Probability Theory</title>
      <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/pss/yisheng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/pss/yisheng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probability is a big subject. My goal for the session will be to give a tour of what kind of maths happens at its core. The basic objects are probability spaces and random variables, which are built on the language of measure theory. My take, however, is that measure theory is just half of the story &amp;ndash; you do not want to do probability on &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; space &amp;hellip; it must be on a space as nice as R. In other words, I would say that the core of probability is about &amp;ldquo;Probability Measures on Metric Spaces&amp;rdquo;. This is the title of a book by K R Parthasarathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the tour centres around this book. I will take some time to explain how one should go from A-Level probability and statistics + mathematical analysis (point set topology, metric spaces) to the starting point of this book. Once we have reached the start of the book, I will give a whirlwind tour on the most important ideas in it. The second part is intended to be a touch-and-go, as a cultural appreciation of the language and the results that one can expect in this field. Come by and have fun with probability!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kepler.gl Mortality</title>
      <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/post/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 21:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/post/post1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provisional results. This is just a test. It&amp;rsquo;s really slow. The &lt;em&gt;compressed&lt;/em&gt; html is 73MB for LSOA London and 123MB for MSOA e0 in England. This is with super-generalised shapefiles too, never mind if we want to get things at 20m resolution for LSOAs. Other annoying things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kepler.gl is slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSOA England level takes even longer to load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It flashes between frames sometimes because it uses a rolling window to animate rather than a point for each year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The year comes up with minutes and seconds and milliseconds and picoseconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The file sizes are too big to put on github without lfs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably need to find a more practical solution for the full result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a play. Show the legend at the side. I would like to make this full screen too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/tutoring/ma20220/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/tutoring/ma20220/week1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
