<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>how-to guide | Jeremy Worsfold</title>
    <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/tag/how-to-guide/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/tag/how-to-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>how-to guide</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 09:44:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/media/face.jpg</url>
      <title>how-to guide</title>
      <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/tag/how-to-guide/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beginners Guide to using Balena</title>
      <link>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/post/balenaguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 09:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/post/balenaguide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This informal guide is for people new to using Balena and effectively want to take code they have written to run on their laptop in something like Python or MATLAB and now run it on Balena. This is by no means exhaustive and there is much more information on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.bath.ac.uk/display/BalenaHPC/Getting&amp;#43;Started&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;wiki page&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, much of the information on Balena here is just condensed from that website. The rest of this guide is general tips on how to transfer files and navigate the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;logging-onto-balena&#34;&gt;Logging onto Balena&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purely-from-a-terminal&#34;&gt;Purely from a terminal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are on campus you can skip the first step and ssh directly into balena&lt;/strong&gt;. Otherwise open a terminal and type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ssh user123@linux.bath.ac.uk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This opens up a link to the uni server (&lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; stands for secure shell). Put in your password and then do the same again but change linux to balena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ssh user123@balena.bath.ac.uk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, you are now in your personal home directory on balena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kitty&#34;&gt;Kitty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the image below taken from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.bath.ac.uk/display/BalenaHPC/Getting&amp;#43;Started&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;wiki page&lt;/a&gt; should be sufficient in explaining how to login using Kitty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jeremyworsfold.github.io/media/kitty.png&#34; alt=&#34;how to login with kitty&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-data-or-files&#34;&gt;Transferring data or files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since you are running your code on balena, you will at some point have to move around data using a terminal so I would recommend doing this for all the steps. The added benefit of this is that your commands are stored so you can always just reuse your previous commands using the up arrows if you can&amp;rsquo;t remember exactly what a command should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To move files between your PC and balena you will sadly have to go through your uni drive unless you are on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-h-drive-to-balena&#34;&gt;From H drive to balena&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can simply copy files across using linux &lt;code&gt;cp&lt;/code&gt; commands and the fact that your &lt;code&gt;H&lt;/code&gt; drive is called &lt;code&gt;$BUCSHOME&lt;/code&gt; on balena. For example, run the command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cp -r folder/with/data $BUCSHOME/destination/folder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to copy a folder with data from balena to your &lt;code&gt;H&lt;/code&gt; drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-local-pc-to-h-drive&#34;&gt;From local PC to H drive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can transfer data to and from University personal drive from your PC by using &lt;code&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt; which stands for secure copy and essentially opens up a &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; portal and then closes it again once the files are transferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sending-files&#34;&gt;Sending files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type one of these &lt;strong&gt;from within a terminal/kitty/putty on your PC&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;scp path/to/directory/f.txt user123@linux.bath.ac.uk:path/to/directory/
scp -r path/to/directory/ user123@linux.bath.ac.uk:path/to/directory/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first will transfer the file &lt;code&gt;file.txt&lt;/code&gt; whereas the second will transfer the whole directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;retrieving-files&#34;&gt;Retrieving files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same as above but with the directories reversed in order, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;scp user123@linux.bath.ac.uk:path/to/remote/directory/file.txt path/to/local/directory/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively if you want, you can use something more familiar which is visual. For linux this would be mounting your Uni drive to your PC using a command called &lt;code&gt;sshfs&lt;/code&gt;. For Windows you can download an application called WinSCP which looks like it hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed since 2005 and basically hasn&amp;rsquo;t but it&amp;rsquo;s neat and very useful if that&amp;rsquo;s your thing. A quick google of either of these should give you the information you need. Finally you can use a browser to do this instead if you would like, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bath.ac.uk/guides/access-and-share-your-work-online-using-files-bath/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-do-i-store-my-files&#34;&gt;Where do I store my files?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I will be the first to admit that I have ran long jobs from my &lt;code&gt;$HOME&lt;/code&gt; directory. This is bad. It will work but it is faster and better apparently to run your jobs in the &lt;code&gt;$SCRATCH&lt;/code&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;ll be tedious at first but getting used to using simple commands like &lt;code&gt;cp&lt;/code&gt; and \verb!ls! will be really helpful. Make sure to save all of your results rather than just plotting graphs at the end, you never know when you might want to alter figures and need the original data again. I would recommend just saving your data and maybe copying it back to your PC to visualise the results. See my guide on how to layout and use a python package for a small research project for more detailed recommendations on how to handle results and plotting for Python specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;jobscripts&#34;&gt;Jobscripts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing you run is the jobscript using the command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sbatch &amp;lt;name of jobscript&amp;gt;.slm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below I&amp;rsquo;ve put in an example jobscript that has been adapted from the one given in the scientific computing module. Make sure you are in the directory of the jobscript when you call it and that the program you want to run is in the same folder or that you have specified where it is in the jobscript.
\lstinputlisting{slurm.txt}
The important bits to check are the job name and the time. For ease I have just made the job name the same as the name of the script you want to run. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain later what the job name is actually used for. Balena allows you free, unlimited usage for jobs which are under 6 hours long so make sure you know approximately how long it will take and change the time given accordingly. Nothing will happen if you overestimate how long you need but it could be helpful for other users to know when their jobs will start if balena is busy and puts your job in ahead of theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using MATLAB and the paralellisation package thing that I know nothing about, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to change the number of tasks per node to the maximum of 16 I imagine. Otherwise, unless you&amp;rsquo;ve done clever things with the &lt;code&gt;MPI4pi&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;multiprocessing&lt;/code&gt; packages in python (which I would highly recommend you learn about if you need to run long programs a lot because this could increase your speed by 16 times or more) then you will probably just be using the one processor and so don&amp;rsquo;t need to change anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;checking-jobs&#34;&gt;Checking Jobs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will get an output file with the extension &lt;code&gt;.out&lt;/code&gt; telling you everything that happens in the job that would normally printed to the screen if you ran it from a terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check your progress or see if the job has started you can find your jobs by typing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;squeue -u user123
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
